<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Dan Atkinson</title>
  <subtitle>Musings by me</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://danatkinson.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-01-27T23:57:00.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://danatkinson.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Dan Atkinson</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How to hack a trusting Windows developer&#39;s machine</title>
    <link href="http://danatkinson.github.io/2017/01/26/How-to-hack-a-trusting-developer-s-machine/"/>
    <id>http://danatkinson.github.io/2017/01/26/How-to-hack-a-trusting-developer-s-machine/</id>
    <published>2017-01-26T22:49:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-01-27T23:57:00.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is based on a post on <a href="https://lifepluslinux.blogspot.co.uk/2017/01/look-before-you-paste-from-website-to.html" target="_blank" rel="external">Life Plus Linux</a> entitled <em>“Look before you paste from website to terminal”</em>.</p>
<p>The post detailed a very simple but cleverly crafted method of giving the user a seemingly benign string to execute into their Linux terminal window.</p>
<p>In this instance, the command looked like <code>ls -lat</code>. This shows all files in the current directory ordered by date. However, between <code>ls</code> and <code>-lat</code> was some text, hidden by some fairly simple CSS. When the text is pasted directly into the terminal, did something the user probably didn’t expect, or indeed want.</p>
<p>I wondered to myself whether this was possible on Windows and so I set about doing exactly that. Not long after, I came up with the following <a href="https://gist.github.com/DanAtkinson/e4e333e1fa40f18a565974481fdced34" target="_blank" rel="external">example</a> which you can try out for yourself.</p>
<p><strong>Go ahead and copy and paste the below into your command prompt:</strong></p>
<p><code style="padding:10px;"><span>dir</span> <span style="color:#EEE;position:absolute;left:-1000px;top:-1000px;height:0px;z-index:-100;display:inline-block;">&amp;<br>  cls &amp; echo Haha! You gave me access to your computer! &amp;<br>      ping 127.0.0.1 -n 2 &gt; nul &amp;<br>      cls &amp; echo h4cking ##                        (10%) &amp;<br>      ping 127.0.0.1 -n 2 &gt; nul &amp;<br>      cls &amp; echo h4cking ###                       (20%) &amp;<br>      ping 127.0.0.1 -n 2 &gt; nul &amp;<br>      cls &amp; echo h4cking #####                     (33%) &amp;<br>      ping 127.0.0.1 -n 2 &gt; nul &amp;<br>      cls &amp; echo h4cking #######                   (40%) &amp;<br>      ping 127.0.0.1 -n 2 &gt; nul &amp;<br>      cls &amp; echo h4cking ##########                (50%) &amp;<br>      ping 127.0.0.1 -n 2 &gt; nul &amp;<br>      cls &amp; echo h4cking #############             (66%) &amp;<br>      ping 127.0.0.1 -n 2 &gt; nul &amp;<br>      cls &amp; echo h4cking #####################     (99%) &amp;<br>      ping 127.0.0.1 -n 2 &gt; nul &amp;<br>      cls &amp; echo h4cking #######################   (100%) &amp;<br>      cls &amp; echo Hacking complete. &amp;<br>      echo Use GUI interface using visual basic to track my IP &amp;<br>      ping 127.0.0.1 -n 5 &gt; nul &amp;<br>      cls<br>      dir </span><span>/w /p<br></span></code></p>
<p>I assure you that <strong><em>this</em></strong> example is safe and will do no harm to your computer, but you should check the contents of your clipboard just to be sure. Below is how it should look if my Markdown blog doesn’t fluff the HTML too much.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/XpkoqnJ.gif" alt=""></p>
<p>Apart from the fact that your command window started spitting out text you weren’t expecting, you might also notice that you didn’t have to press enter/return - Windows actually interprets the line breaks as new lines and executes it accordingly. So, unless you examine your clipboard contents first in a text editor like Notepad, you could be executing something that can cause <strong><em>very serious damage</em></strong> to your machine.</p>
<p>Whilst, that little example above is jokey, it’s really not too difficult to take it and turn it into something far more <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fork_bomb" target="_blank" rel="external">malicious</a>. Given the propensity for many developers to use a command prompt with administrative privileges, the possibilities are somewhat worrying.</p>
<p>It’s far too easy for a developer to simply copy and paste code into a command prompt. This is even more so when there are sites like <a href="https://chocolatey.org/" target="_blank" rel="external">Chocolatey</a> which are proponents of doing this (full disclosure, I’m a member of the <a href="https://github.com/orgs/chocolatey/people" target="_blank" rel="external">Chocolatey organisation</a>).</p>
<p>If you’re interested, I created a fully-functioning  <a href="https://gist.github.com/DanAtkinson/e4e333e1fa40f18a565974481fdced34" target="_blank" rel="external">Github Gist</a> example which you can try locally. And here is the HTML for the <code>dir /w /p</code> example.</p>
<pre><code>&lt;code style=&quot;background-color:#eeeeee;padding:10px;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;dir&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&quot;color:#F3F5F6;position:absolute;left:-100px;top:-100px;height:0px;z-index:-100;display:inline-block;&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;
    cls &amp;amp; echo Haha! You gave me access to your computer! &amp;amp;
    ping 127.0.0.1 -n 2 &amp;gt; nul &amp;amp;
    cls &amp;amp; echo h4cking ##                        (10%) &amp;amp;
    ping 127.0.0.1 -n 2 &amp;gt; nul &amp;amp;
    cls &amp;amp; echo h4cking ###                       (20%) &amp;amp;
    ping 127.0.0.1 -n 2 &amp;gt; nul &amp;amp;
    cls &amp;amp; echo h4cking #####                     (33%) &amp;amp;
    ping 127.0.0.1 -n 2 &amp;gt; nul &amp;amp;
    cls &amp;amp; echo h4cking #######                   (40%) &amp;amp;
    ping 127.0.0.1 -n 2 &amp;gt; nul &amp;amp;
    cls &amp;amp; echo h4cking ##########                (50%) &amp;amp;
    ping 127.0.0.1 -n 2 &amp;gt; nul &amp;amp;
    cls &amp;amp; echo h4cking #############             (66%) &amp;amp;
    ping 127.0.0.1 -n 2 &amp;gt; nul &amp;amp;
    cls &amp;amp; echo h4cking #####################     (99%) &amp;amp;
    ping 127.0.0.1 -n 2 &amp;gt; nul &amp;amp;
    cls &amp;amp; echo h4cking #######################   (100%) &amp;amp;
    cls &amp;amp; echo Hacking complete. &amp;amp;
    echo Use GUI interface using visual basic to track my IP &amp;amp;
    ping 127.0.0.1 -n 5 &amp;gt; nul &amp;amp;
    cls 
    &lt;br&gt;dir
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;/w /p&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
</code></pre>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;This is based on a post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://lifepluslinux.blogspot.co.uk/2017/01/look-before-you-paste-from-website-to.html&quot; target=&quot;_bla
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Saluton, Mondo!</title>
    <link href="http://danatkinson.github.io/2017/01/26/Saluton-Mondo/"/>
    <id>http://danatkinson.github.io/2017/01/26/Saluton-Mondo/</id>
    <published>2017-01-26T21:40:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-01-26T22:27:08.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Or ‘Hello, World’!</p>
<p>I remember the first time I used those words. It was October 2003. After dabbling in programming for a few years, I finally took the plunge and decided to make a career out of it by signing up to do a computing course - HND Computing (Software Engineering) - at <a href="http://www.hull-college.ac.uk" target="_blank" rel="external">Hull College</a> followed by a top-up year to BSc at the <a href="https://www.lincoln.ac.uk/" target="_blank" rel="external">University of Lincoln</a>.</p>
<p>I’d been to Hull College a few years previous to do a GNVQ in Advanced Science. I ended up getting accepted to a course in Aberdeen but decided that I’d make more money working at McDonald’s as a manager than I would as a fully qualified geneticist, so I followed the money until I finally realised how soul-sucking McDonald’s was.</p>
<p>But I digress…</p>
<p>I’ve accumulated several programming books over the years. My favourite is still <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/d/Books/Software-Engineering-Ian-Sommerville/0137035152" target="_blank" rel="external">Software Engineering</a> by Ian Sommerville. It’s required reading on practically any course. My first, however, was a book about Java. I forget the name of it, and a quick search of my Amazon order history going back to 2002 doesn’t show it so I must have bought it in one of those old-timey bookshops people used to go to.</p>
<p>In it, were the immortal words at the top of this post. <code>Saluton, Mondo!</code>. Even now, I still prefer those over Hello, World. No idea why.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Or ‘Hello, World’!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I used those words. It was October 2003. After dabbling in programming for a few year
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
